# Shuvozit Ghose

\$\Lambda +1-431-554-2105\$ \subsection \text{shuvozit.ghose@gmail.com } \setminus \frac{\lambda}{\shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \text{\$\Quad}\$ \ \ \quad \text{shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \ \quad \text{shuvozitghose}\$ \ \ \ \quad \text{ShuvozitGhose}\$ \ \ \quad \text{ShuvozitGhose}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Shuvozitghose}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \text{Shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \text{Shuvozitghose.github.io}\$ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \quad \text{Canada}\$ \ \quad \quad

## Summary

An Artificial Intelligence (AI) or Machine Learning(ML) engineer/researcher with 5+ years of hands-on experience in machine learning research and development with publications at top conferences (like CVPR, ICCV, ICPR, ICASSP). My expertise encompasses a profound understanding of key machine learning or deep learning concepts, coupled with a comprehensive grasp of data preprocessing, model training, and effective deployment strategies. My practical work has spanned diverse machine-learning techniques, including prompt learning, Large language models (LLMs), graph neural networks, Transformers, graphical models, dimension reduction, clustering, classification, regression techniques, etc.

#### Education

M.Sc. — Computer Science

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023

University of Manitoba, Canada

Computer Vision Lab DGPA: 4.20/4.50.

Research Field: Computer Vision, NLP, Foundation Model, LLM and Deep Learning

Thesis: CLIP for Point Cloud Understanding Advisors: Prof. Yang Wang and Prof. Yiming Qian

Examiners: Prof. Lorenzo Livi and Prof Carson Kai-Sang Leung

Status: Completed M.Sc. in October 2023.

Google Scholar Citations: 175 (h-index: 7) Google Scholar

Bachelor of Technology — Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

Maulana Abul Kalam Azad Univ. of Tech.(IEM), India

### Technical Skills —

DGPA: 8.87/10.

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, SQL, Python (5 Years+). Source Control: Git, GitHub

Deep Learning Frameworks: Tensorflow, PyTorch (5 Years+). DevOps: CI/CD, Kubernetes

Big Data Platform: Hadoop, Map-Reduce, Hive, Hbase, Pig, Scoop.. Cloud Frameworks: Azure (1 Year).

## **Professional Experience**

#### Graduate Research Assistant | University of Manitoba

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023 | Canada

- Developed 3D Generative AI-based point cloud recognition model utilizing Large language models (LLMs) and image-based geometric deep learning models using Python and Pytorch.
- Developed point cloud classification model performing 3D shape analysis, topology analysis, view geometry analysis, functional mapping, and geometric deep learning.
- Developed Multi-modal deep learning for point cloud classification by connecting Large language models (LLMs) with image models.
- Computed inference using PyTorch on both CPU and GPU running CUDA 11.2 (@Acc > 90%).

#### Graduate Teaching Assistant | University of Manitoba

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023 | Canada

- Collaborated with the instructor and led the lab for undergraduate students for course Comp 2140 (data structure and algorithm using Java).
- Collaborated with the instructor and Graded courses COMP 4360 (machine learning using Python), COMP 2150 (object orientation using Java, C++, and Javascript), COMP 3350 (Software Engineering using Java and Android Studio), and COMP 3490 (Computer Graphics I using processing).

## Research Intern | University of Surrey

June 2020 – Mar 2021 | UK

- Developed deep learning model for 2D image and text recognition exploiting neural network architectures, regularization techniques, learning techniques, loss functions, optimization strategies, etc using Python and PyTorch.
- Developed transformer-based 2D text image recognition model for handwriting and scene text recognition using TensorFlow.

#### **Achievements**

- 1. Awarded University of Manitoba Graduate Fellowship (UMGF) at the University of Manitoba 2022-2023.
- 2. Awarded International Graduate Student Entrance Scholarship (IGSES) at the University of Manitoba 2021.
- 3. Got NPTEL Elite Certification in Deep Learning for Visual Computing, 2018.

Research Background —			
<ul><li>(i) Large Language Model (LLM)</li><li>(iv) Self-supervised Learning</li><li>(vii) Prompt Learning &amp; Foundation Model</li><li>(vii) Diffusion models</li></ul>	<ul><li>(ii) Graph Neural Network (GNN)</li><li>(v) Transfomers</li><li>(viii) Large vision Larguage model (LVLM)</li><li>(viii) Convoltuion Neural Network (CNN)</li></ul>	(vi) Reii (ix) Sen	nerative AI nforcement Learning ni-supervised Learning a-Learning
Publications —			
C7 fication Shuvozit Ghose, Yang Wang	ask Sampling for CLIP-based Point Cloud Cl	assi-	April 2024
Conference on Robots and Vision (CRV)(Ord	ul)	<u>PDF</u>	
Joint Visual Semantic Reasoning: Multi-Stage Decoder for Text Recognition  Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Aneeshan Sain, Amandeep Kumar, Shuvozit Ghose, Pinaki Nath Chehury, Yi-Zhe Song  IEEE Conference on International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)		owd- <i>PDF</i>	Oct 2021
MetaHTR: Towards Writer-Adaptive Handwritten Text Recognition  Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Shuvozit Ghose, Amandeep Kumar, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Aneesl Sain, Yi-Zhe Song			June 2021
Modeling Extent-of-Texture Information for Ground Terrain Recognition C4 Shuvozit Ghose, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Partha Pratim Roy, Umapada Pal IEEE International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)		<u>PDF</u>	Sept 2020
UDBNET: Unsupervised Document Binarization Network via Adversarial Game  Amandeep Kumar*, Shuvozit Ghose*, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Partha Pratim Roy, Umapada Pal (* equal Contributions)			Sept 2020
IEEE International Conference on Pattern Re		<u>PDF</u>	
Fractional Local Neighborhood Intensity Pattern for Image Retrieval using Genetic Algorithm  C2 Shuvozit Ghose, Abhirup Das, Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Partha Pratim Roy  Multimedia Tools and Applications  PDF			Sept 2020
A Deep One-Shot Network for Query-based Logo Retrieval  Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Ankan Kumar Bhunia, Shuvozit Ghose, Abhirup Das, Partha Pratim Roy, Umapada Pal)			July 2019

### References

Pattern Recognition

Dr. Yang Wang

Phone: +1-514-848-2424 ext 8596

**PDF** 

<u>PDF</u>

May 2019

Associate Professor Email: yang.wang@concordia.ca Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering

Concordia University, Canada

User Constrained Thumbnail Generation Using Adaptive Convolutions

CO Perla Sai Raj Kishore, Ayan Kumar Bhunia, **Shuvozit Ghose**, Partha Pratim Roy *International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)* 

Dr. Yiming Qian

Applied Scientist Email: qym.ustc@gmail.com
Amazon

Canada

Dr. Ruppa ThulasiramPhone: +1-204-474-6538ProfessorEmail: tulsi.thulasiram@umanitoba.ca

Department of Computer Science University of Manitoba, Canada